好的，现在我们来到了 CLI 博客，这是我们的第一个应用程序。
Okay, so we're at the CLI Blog, our first app.
这是一个有曲折的博客。
It's a blog with a twist.
这是一个 CLI 博客。
It's a CLI Blog.
[笑] 所以，这是你最喜欢的，它是一个图表。
[LAUGH] So, it's your favorite, it's a graph.
[笑] 所以我们有一个，这些就是我们要做的，
[LAUGH] So we have a, these are what we're gonna do,
这有点像交互地图。
it's kinda like the map of interactions.
我们有一个起点和
We have a starting point and
我们将看看是否有任何作者可以直接进入菜单。
we're gonna see if we have any authors we can go straight to menu.
如果我们没有任何作者，我们将转到底部的创建作者。
If we don't have any authors, we go to Create Author down at the bottom here.
创建作者后，我们返回菜单。
And after we create the author, we go back to menu.
从菜单我们可以看到所有的帖子，去看看最新的帖子。
From menu we can see all the posts, go see the latest posts.
去创造更多的作者。
Go create more authors.
我们可以去写，但写不会回到菜单。
We can go Write, but Write doesn't go back to menu.
写完后会更新到最新，因为你刚刚写了它，
Write goes up to the latest after its done cuz you just wrote it,
你想在这里看到它。
you wanna see it here.
所以这就是我们正在做的事情的地图，世界地图。
So this is kind of the map, world map of what we're doing.
我们会看到我们能走多远。
We'll see how far we get.
我真的只关心架构决策和
I really just care about working on the architectural decisions and
以实用的方式制作这个应用程序。
making this app in a functional way.
比我更喜欢完成所有的小螺母和螺栓来完成这项工作。
More so than I do like completing all the little nuts and bolts to make this work.
那么让我们看看我们可以在分配的时间内做些什么。
So let's see what we can do in the time allotted.
回到我们的 VS 代码。
Get back to our VS code.
我们将从这里的这个小设置开始。
We're gonna start with this little setup here.
我们有问答界面。
We have a question and answer interface.
它的工作原理是这样的，我们可以调用 getInput。
And it works like so, we can call getInput.
所以，然后，我可以映射它，然后
So, and then, I can map over that and
就像，无论 xx 到大写是什么。
be like, whatever x x to UpperCase it's.
所以我们现在只是在处理一个任务，但是
And so we're just dealing inside a task now but
这是我对这个问题的回答，对。
this is my answer to that question, right.
所以，这将在控制台中提出问题，然后我会得到我的答案。
So, this will pose the question in the console and then I'll get my answer back.
让我们运行它。
Let's just run that.
只要确保它有效console.error console.log。
Just make sure it works console.error console.log.
我们运行它。
We run it.
仍然试图摆脱那些弹出窗口，无法做到。
Still try to get rid of those pop ups, cannot do it.
感谢 VS 代码，好的。
Thanks VS code, all right.
大概是我的错
It's probably my fault.
我敢肯定，这不是他们的错。
It's not their fault I'm sure.
所以转到博客索引，然后像现在一样设置，你去吧。
So go to blog index and so set like now, there you go.
酷，有应用程序。
Cool, there's the app.
我们完成了。
We're done.
感受那份幸运。
Feel that luck.
所以这很整洁。
So this is neat.
这只是与我们刚刚在任务中抓住它的界面重新对齐一起出现的。
This kinda just comes with the interface realign we just grabbed it in the task.
所以我想开始做的是回顾那个
So what I want to start by doing is looking back at that
我们有一张世界地图，我想勾勒出其中的一些功能，然后
kinda world map we have, I'd like to just sketch out some of these functions and
有点看看这些函数的类型是什么。
kinda see what the type of these functions are.
而要做到这一点，我只需要写一些粗略的一厢情愿的代码。
And to do so, I just have to write some rough like wishful thinking code.
所以我不会去实施一切。
So I'm not gonna go implement everything.
我只是会有点松散地写东西
I'm just gonna kinda loosely write stuff and
然后看看我们可能需要什么作为函数模型。
then see what we might need as a function model.
所以从开始。
So start with Start.
这是开始 [笑] 发挥作用的好地方。
It's a good place to start [LAUGH] to function.
我想我们会，首先，我们要检查一下是否有任何作者，对吗？
I guess we'll, first, we're gonna check to see if there's any authors, right?
所以我们能做的是，我相信我们会带来一个小阵列
So what we can do is, I believe we're gonna bring in a little array
我想我以前准备的基于数据库。
based database that I think I've previously prepared.
看看这是不是在这里，它在lib中，好吧。
See if this is here, it's in lib, okay.
所以我们有这个小数据库。
So we have this little database.
其实我去看看它导出的Dbx，
Actually, let me go take a look at Dbx it exports,
保存查找所有和商店。
save find all and the store.
好的，很酷，这只是我们正在处理包含在任务中的数组。
Okay, cool and this just we're working with arrays wrapped in a task.
我是，如果我们有时间，我会进入策略模式或
I was, if we had time I would have gone into the strategy pattern or
这里有一些东西，但我们在，它真的既不在这里也不在那里。
something in here but we are, it's really neither here nor there.
所以我们已经保存了所有，这就是我们真正需要的。
So we have save all and that's all we really need.
也许我们可以使用 find ，但要专注于此。
We could use find maybe, but focus on that.
所以它的工作方式是我想我们会说我们必须给它一个表名。
So the way this works is I guess we'll say all we have to give it a table name.
所以让我们像作者表一样给它，只是作者。
So let's give it like author table, just authors.
所以给它表名。
So give it the table name.
然后那会，我可以改变那个和
And then that will, I can change over that and
得到，所以这是一个任务。
get, so this is a task.
实际上，现在只需映射它并获取作者。
Actually just map over it right now and get the authors.
我们会说如果我们有作者，我们会
And we'll say if we have authors, we're gonna
否则进入菜单，我们要去创建作者。
go into the menu otherwise, we're gonna go to Create Author.
好吧，再一次，这些都没有实现。
All right now, again, none of this is implemented.
看起来这是另一个函数，对该函数的一些映射和
It looks like this is another function, some mapping over this function and
返回另一个函数，这有点奇怪。
returning another function, that's a little weird.
我们只需要密切关注这一点。
We'll have to just keep an eye on that.
那么 CreateAuthor 是什么样子的呢？
So what does CreateAuthor look like?
让我们通过这三个功能
And let's just get through these maybe three functions and
然后我们会看看我们在处理什么。
then we'll kinda see what we're dealing with.
随着我们制作更多的功能，我们可能不得不回来重构，
And as we make more functions, we might have to come back and refactor,
走着瞧吧。
see what happens.
但是 CreateAuthor，把它画出来。
But CreateAuthor, sketch that out.
好吧，那会是什么样子？
All right, what would that look like?
好吧，我们会问，我们会得到输入 On，比如说，name。
Well, we'll ask, we'll get the input On, let's say, name.
然后当我们得到输入时，我们得到，
And then when we get the input back, we get,
我一直直接使用链条，但我不确定我是否需要链条。
I keep going straight to chain, but I'm not really sure if I need the chain yet.
所以我们得到了作者姓名。
So we get back the author name.
让我们继续制作一个带名字的小作者类型。
Let's go ahead and make a little author type that takes a name.
有趣的是，这真的没什么。
And the interesting thing about that is it's really nothing.
它只是要选择一个名字，把它打成一个类型。
It's just going to pick a name, slap it in a type.
我喜欢这样做的原因
And the reason I like to do this, in a more typed
正式语言，或者如果我们有一堂课或其他任何我们想要的东西，
formal language ,or if we had a class or whatever else we would,
它保持您定义的数据类型，以便
it keeps your data types defined so that
您不仅可以随心所欲地在整个应用程序中创建数据类型。
you're not just willy nilly creating data types all throughout your app as you go.
就像这个乘客构造函数一样，
And so like this passenger constructor,
即使它除了放入一个对象之外并没有真正做任何事情。
even though it's not really doing anything besides putting in an object.
然后我们将继续进行映射。
Then we'll go ahead and map over that.
所以我们有一个作者，我们该怎么办？
So we have an author and what do we do with that?
我想现在我们已经创建了一个作者，我们可能必须将它保存在数据库中。
I guess now that we've created an author, we probably have to save it in the DB.
好的，这将是一个链条。
Okay, so that'll be a chain.
或者不，让我们只是，那里有一张地图。
Or no, let's just, that's a map there.
这是链条，是的。
And this is chain, yeah.
所以将它保存在数据库中，再次保存在作者表中。
So save this in the DB, again in the author table.
所以保存在这里，我们将保存作者，然后最后我们必须将其映射到，
So save here, we're gonna save the author and then finally we have to map that into,
我们真的不在乎我们拯救了作者，只要它，
we don't really care that we saved the author as long as it,
我想这会拒绝任务，如果它不保存。
I imagine this will reject the task if it doesn't save.
我们可以通过多种方式改造数据库，我们可以有一个任务
We could remodel the database in a number of ways, we could have a task either right
数据库连接可能是任务失败的原因，然后它仍然有
where the DB connection might be why the task fails, and then it still has
如果没有保存作者，则是一个成功的任务，其中包含错误。
a successful task with an error inside it if it didn't save the author.
做一些验证，
Do some validations,
也许我们将使用我们的验证库与作者合作。
perhaps we will use our validation library to work with the author.
但现在我只想说什么。
But right now I'm just going to say whatever.
让我们勾勒出这些。
Let's just sketch these out.
我会说菜单是我们要去的地方，对吧。
I'm gonna say menu is where we'll go from there, right.
我们有一个作者，现在我们要去菜单。
We have an author and now we're going to menu.
如果我们回顾一下我们的小地图，每次我们创建一个作者，
And if we look back at our little map, every time we create an author,
我回到菜单。
I go back to menu.
没有其他地方可去，所以我就直接去那里。
There's nowhere else to go, so I'm just going to go right there.
最后一个，让我们继续写菜单，这是一个有趣的。
Last one, let's go ahead and write menu, it's a fun one.
菜单，让我们看看，你今天想去哪里？
Menu, Let's see, where do you want to go today?
微信？ 1991年？
MSN? 1991?
我们会，也许私人提供一个提示，我们想要像创建作者一样，
And we'll, maybe private provide a hint, do we want to do like create author,
写，都是她最新的。
write, all her latest.
好吧，很酷，因为有一些关于我们实际上可以做什么的提示，并且
All right, cool, because there's some some hints at what we can actually do and
我想，一旦我们得到输入，我们就得到了路线。
once we get that input, we get the route, I suppose.
我们需要一个小路由器，所以我们要做一个路由器，我们将传入路由。
We'll need a little router, so we'll do a router, we'll pass in the route.
那将是，看看这个，我们只是传递这些延续，
And that will be, look at this, we're just passing these continuations along,
现在我看到了，对吧？
now that I see it, right?
所以，一旦我把路由器传出去，让我们继续写一个小路由器，
So, once I'm passing the router out, let's go ahead and write a little router,
然后我们将完成我们的小草图，让我们把它放在这里。
and then we'll finish our little sketch, let's put this down here.
其中一件事是我们正在定义这些功能和
And one of the things about this is we're defining these functions and
如果我在定义这些函数之前提到它们，JavaScript 不会喜欢它。
JavaScript will not like it if I mention this functions before they're defined.
但是因为它们在这里的函数内部，所以他们不在乎。
But since they're inside functions here, they don't care of that.
我可以在那里打电话给路由器，但是
I can call router within there but
我必须在这里写下路由器，开始，菜单。
I have to write the router down here, Start, Menu.
好吧，我们不想让人们回到起点，所以
Well, we don't want to let people go back to the start, so
这甚至是不可能的。
that's not even a possibility.
在菜单中，createAuthor，我们可以添加更多。
In Menu, createAuthor and we can add more.
好吧，美好的时光。
All right, good times.